<<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Drake Folk</name>
    <description></description>
    <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/7xW50nukB5Vq"> lolmatter0</author>
      <update version="0.3">
			  <file name="race-drakefolk.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Lolm0/Project-Reagan/RWS-EXPERIMENTAL/race-drakefolk.xml"/>
		  </update>
  </info>

<element name="Drake Folk" type="Race" source="Reagan World Setting" id="ID_LM0_RWS_RACE_DRAKEFOLK">
  <description>
      <p class="flavor"> The Drake-folk are an elusive species, often regarded as either exceptional warriors or descendants of renowned fighters. They are widely recognized for their sense of pride, strength, and nobility. </p>
      <h4>ORIGINS</h4>
      <p> These mystical beings are formed through the mystical energy emanating from the body of a deceased dragon. As natural sorcerers, dragons possess an inherent magical essence that permeates their surroundings. However, it is important to note that not all members of the Drake-folk race are the result of exposure to this energy, as some are born into the race. </p>
      <p class="indent"> When two Drake-folk parents have a child, the child is referred to as a true Drake-folk, and there is no distinction between a true Drake-folk and a child born to a Drake-folk and another race. </p>
      <h4>DRAKE FOLK TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Drake folk have personal names given at birth, but they put their clan names first as a mark of honor. A childhood name or nickname is often used among clutchmates as a descriptive term or a term of endearment. The name might recall an event or center on a habit.</p>
			<p>
			<b>Male Names: </b>Drakar, Vorin, Kaelum, Thoren, Zephyrion, Rygar, Baelok, Darian, Azrak, Pyrrhus, Valthor, Gavrek, Tyndar, Korvash, Xandor, Bracius, Ignar
			<br/>
			<b>Female Names: </b>Seraphina, Lyssandra, Valeria, Astrid, Nymeria, Elowen, Sylvara, Isolde, Thalassa, Elysia, Lirael, Vaelora, Zephyra, Amara, Nyxaria, Evelindra, Solara
			<br/>
			<b>Clan Names: </b>Clethtinthiallor, Daardendrian, Delmirev, Drachedandion, Fenkenkabradon, Kepeshkmolik, Kerrhylon, Kimbatuul, Linxakasendalor, Myastan, Nemmonis, Norixius, Ophinshtalajiir, Prexijandilin, Shestendeliath, Turnuroth, Verthisathurgiesh, Yarjerit
      <br/>
			</p>
      <h4>DRAKE FOLK TRAITS</h4>
      <p> Your draconic mutations or heritage manifests in a variety of traits shared with other Drake-folk. </p>
      <p>
      <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your strength increases by 2, and your dexterity score increases by 1.
      <br />
      <span class="feature">Age.</span>Drake-folk, when young, experience a slow rate of growth. They only reach the size and development of a 10-year-old human by the time they reach 30 years of age, and they only reach adulthood by the time they are 60 years old. The longest recorded lifespan of a natural Drake-folk was 650 years. However, if a Drake-folk was created by radiation, their age is determined by their previous race, with an additional 75 years added to their lifespan.
      <br />
      <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Drake folk tend toward no particular alignment. The best and worst are found among them.
      <br />
      <span class="feature">Size.</span>Your size is determined by your previous race. If you were born as a Drake-folk, you will typically be taller and heavier than a human, standing at over 6 feet tall and weighing almost 250 pounds on average. However, regardless of your race, your size is considered Medium.
      <br />
      <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
      <br />
      <span class="feature">Languages</span>You can speak, read, and write Common, Draconic, and another language.
      <br/>
			</p>
    </description>

  <sheet display="false"/>

  <setters>
      <set name="names" type="male">Drakar, Vorin, Kaelum, Thoren, Zephyrion, Rygar, Baelok, Darian, Azrak, Pyrrhus, Valthor, Gavrek, Tyndar, Korvash, Xandor, Bracius, Ignar</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Seraphina, Lyssandra, Valeria, Astrid, Nymeria, Elowen, Sylvara, Isolde, Thalassa, Elysia, Lirael, Vaelora, Zephyra, Amara, Nyxaria, Evelindra, Solara</set>
      <set name="names" type="clan">Clethtinthiallor, Daardendrian, Delmirev, Drachedandion, Fenkenkabradon, Kepeshkmolik, Kerrhylon, Kimbatuul, Linxakasendalor, Myastan, Nemmonis, Norixius, Ophinshtalajiir, Prexijandilin, Shestendeliath, Turnuroth, Verthisathurgiesh, Yarjerit</set>
      <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clam}}</set>
      <set name="height" modifier="2d8">5'8"</set>
      <set name="weight" modifier="2d6">250 lb.</set>
    </setters>

  <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="2"/>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1"/>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC"/>
      <select type="Language" name="Language (DrakeFolk)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
    </rules>
  </element> 
</elements>
