<element name="Wolf-folk" type="Race" source="Reagan World Setting" id="ID_RACE_WOLF_FOLK">
    <compendium display="false" />
    <description>
        <p>Wolf-folk are a rare sight in the world, and due to their physical resemblance to werewolves, they are often mistaken for the latter. This has made it challenging for them to form a distinct identity as a separate race. Wolf-folk are a resilient people, and they continue to preserve and celebrate their culture despite their rarity in the world.</p>
    </description>
    <traits>
        <element name="Ability Score Increase (Constitution)" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>Your constitution score increases by 2.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Increase (Dexterity)" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>Your dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Age" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>At the age of 5, young Wolf-folk attain the size and development equivalent to a 10-year-old human, and reach adulthood at the age of 10. Their lifespan can last up to around 200 years, providing them with a longer life compared to many other races.</p>
            </description>
        </element>
        <element name="Alignment" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>Wolf-folk tend to remain neutral in most arguments, as they tend to uphold their natural instincts and avoid taking sides. They prioritize maintaining a sense of balance and harmony, rather than engaging in disputes that can disrupt the peace.</p>
            </description>
        </element>
        <element name="Size" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>Wolf-folk are typically taller and heavier than humans, standing at a height of well over 6 feet and weighing an average of almost 250 pounds. Despite their larger size, they are still classified as a medium-sized race.</p>
            </description>
        </element>
        <element name="Speed" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <speed value="30" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Languages" type="Racial Trait" source="Animali Example">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>You can speak, read, and write Common, and another language.</p>
            </description>
        </element>
    </traits>
</element>
